<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:prism="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/prism/">
  <channel>
    <title>Brain Current Issue</title>
    <link>http://academic.oup.com/brain</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 04:53:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Silverchair</generator>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2232/5059463">
      <title>Unstable non-coding pentanucleotide repeats destabilize cortical excitability</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2232/5059463?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Guerrini R, Mei D. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;This scientific commentary refers to ‘Intronic pentanucleotide TTTCA repeat insertion in the &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SAMD12&lt;/span&gt; gene causes familial cortical myoclonic tremor with epilepsy type 1’, by Cen &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;et al.&lt;/span&gt;. (doi:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="article.aspx?volume=&amp;amp;page="&gt;10.1093/brain/awy160&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2232
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2235
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy196
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy196</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2235/5059468">
      <title>Peripheral blood neurofilament light chain levels: the neurologist’s C-reactive protein?</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2235/5059468?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Giovannoni G. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;This scientific commentary refers to ‘Serum neurofilament as a predictor of disease worsening and brain and spinal cord atrophy in multiple sclerosis’, by Barro &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;et al.&lt;/span&gt;. (doi:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="article.aspx?volume=&amp;amp;page="&gt;10.1093/brain/awy154&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2235
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2237
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy200
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy200</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2237/5059438">
      <title>Which is to blame for cognitive decline in ageing: amyloid deposition, neurodegeneration or both?</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2237/5059438?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Gonneaud J, Chételat G. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;This scientific commentary refers to ‘Effects of amyloid pathology and neurodegeneration on cognitive change in cognitively normal adults’, by Bilgel &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;et al.&lt;/span&gt;. (doi:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="article.aspx?volume=&amp;amp;page="&gt;10.1093/brain/awy150&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2237
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2241
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy174
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy174</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2241/5059473">
      <title>Spectral signatures of neurodegenerative diseases: how to decipher them?</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2241/5059473?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Meder D, Siebner H. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;This scientific commentary refers to ‘Neurophysiological signatures of Alzheimer’s disease and frontotemporal lobar degeneration: pathology versus phenotype’ by Sami &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;et al.&lt;/span&gt;. (doi:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="article.aspx?volume=&amp;amp;page="&gt;10.1093/brain/awy180&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and ‘Reorganization of cortical oscillatory dynamics underlying disinhibition in frontotemporal dementia’ by Hughes &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;et al.&lt;/span&gt;. (doi:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="article.aspx?volume=&amp;amp;page="&gt;10.1093/brain/awy176&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2241
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2244
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy195
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy195</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2231/5059471">
      <title>Editorial</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2231/5059471?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Kullmann D. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;Clarivate Analytics recently released the latest Journal Impact Factors. Before saying any more, I refer the reader to the San Francisco Declaration on Research Assessment (sfdora.org), which summarizes a number of compelling arguments against using the Impact Factor (or, by implication, any other journal prestige metric) as ‘a surrogate measure of the quality of individual research articles, to assess an individual scientist’s contributions, or in hiring, promotion, or funding decisions’. Among DORA supporters and signatories are major research funders such as Wellcome, over 12 000 individuals, and several dozen journals. Some of these periodicals will be familiar to the reader but others not, such as the &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Journal of Negative and No Positive Results.&lt;/span&gt; Other journals with improbable names are missing from DORA, including &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Small&lt;/span&gt; (which has a sizeable IF of 9.598), &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Soft Matter&lt;/span&gt; (3.709) and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Silence&lt;/span&gt;, which went forever quiet in 2014 without ever achieving an Impact Factor despite focusing on the hot topic of RNA interference.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2231
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2231
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy201
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy201</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2511/5055414">
      <title>Acute ketamine dysregulates task-related gamma-band oscillations in thalamo-cortical circuits in schizophrenia</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2511/5055414?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Grent-‘t-Jong T, Rivolta D, Gross J, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Hypofunction of the &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;N&lt;/span&gt;-methyl-&lt;span style="text-transform:lowercase;font-variant:small-caps;"&gt;d&lt;/span&gt;-aspartate receptor (NMDAR) has been implicated as a possible mechanism underlying cognitive deficits and aberrant neuronal dynamics in schizophrenia. To test this hypothesis, we first administered a sub-anaesthetic dose of S-ketamine (0.006 mg/kg/min) or saline in a single-blind crossover design in 14 participants while magnetoencephalographic data were recorded during a visual task. In addition, magnetoencephalographic data were obtained in a sample of unmedicated first-episode psychosis patients (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;n = &lt;/span&gt;10) and in patients with chronic schizophrenia (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;n = &lt;/span&gt;16) to allow for comparisons of neuronal dynamics in clinical populations versus NMDAR hypofunctioning. Magnetoencephalographic data were analysed at source-level in the 1–90 Hz frequency range in occipital and thalamic regions of interest. In addition, directed functional connectivity analysis was performed using Granger causality and feedback and feedforward activity was investigated using a directed asymmetry index. Psychopathology was assessed with the Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale. Acute ketamine administration in healthy volunteers led to similar effects on cognition and psychopathology as observed in first-episode and chronic schizophrenia patients. However, the effects of ketamine on high-frequency oscillations and their connectivity profile were not consistent with these observations. Ketamine increased amplitude and frequency of gamma-power (63–80 Hz) in occipital regions and upregulated low frequency (5–28 Hz) activity. Moreover, ketamine disrupted feedforward and feedback signalling at high and low frequencies leading to hypo- and hyper-connectivity in thalamo-cortical networks. In contrast, first-episode and chronic schizophrenia patients showed a different pattern of magnetoencephalographic activity, characterized by decreased task-induced high-gamma band oscillations and predominantly increased feedforward/feedback-mediated Granger causality connectivity. Accordingly, the current data have implications for theories of cognitive dysfunctions and circuit impairments in the disorder, suggesting that acute NMDAR hypofunction does not recreate alterations in neural oscillations during visual processing observed in schizophrenia.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2511
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2526
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy175
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy175</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2289/5054138">
      <title>A novel complex neurological phenotype due to a homozygous mutation in FDX2</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2289/5054138?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Gurgel-Giannetti J, Lynch D, Paiva A, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Defects in iron–sulphur [Fe-S] cluster biogenesis are increasingly recognized as causing neurological disease. Mutations in a number of genes that encode proteins involved in mitochondrial [Fe-S] protein assembly lead to complex neurological phenotypes. One class of proteins essential in the early cluster assembly are ferredoxins. FDX2 is ubiquitously expressed and is essential in the &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;de novo&lt;/span&gt; formation of [2Fe-2S] clusters in humans. We describe and genetically define a novel complex neurological syndrome identified in two Brazilian families, with a novel homozygous mutation in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;FDX2.&lt;/span&gt; Patients were clinically evaluated, underwent MRI, nerve conduction studies, EMG and muscle biopsy. To define the genetic aetiology, a combination of homozygosity mapping and whole exome sequencing was performed. We identified six patients from two apparently unrelated families with autosomal recessive inheritance of a complex neurological phenotype involving optic atrophy and nystagmus developing by age 3, followed by myopathy and recurrent episodes of cramps, myalgia and muscle weakness in the first or second decade of life. Sensory-motor axonal neuropathy led to progressive distal weakness. MRI disclosed a reversible or partially reversible leukoencephalopathy. Muscle biopsy demonstrated an unusual pattern of regional succinate dehydrogenase and cytochrome &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; oxidase deficiency with iron accumulation. The phenotype was mapped in both families to the same homozygous missense mutation in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;FDX2&lt;/span&gt; (c.431C &amp;gt; T, p.P144L). The deleterious effect of the mutation was validated by real-time reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction and western blot analysis, which demonstrated normal expression of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;FDX2&lt;/span&gt; mRNA but severely reduced expression of FDX2 protein in muscle tissue. This study describes a novel complex neurological phenotype with unusual MRI and muscle biopsy features, conclusively mapped to a mutation in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;FDX2&lt;/span&gt;, which encodes a ubiquitously expressed mitochondrial ferredoxin essential for early [Fe-S] cluster biogenesis.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2289
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2298
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy172
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy172</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2527/5050904">
      <title>Brenda Milner on her 100th birthday: a lifetime of ‘good ideas’</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2527/5050904?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Watkins K, Klein D. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;Figure 1As Brenda Milner celebrates her 100&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; birthday, Watkins and Klein – two of her former postdocs and now colleagues and friends – look back at the impact and legacy of her work, and the reasons for her continued success.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2527
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2532
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy186
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy186</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2299/5049404">
      <title>BCL11B mutations in patients affected by a neurodevelopmental disorder with reduced type 2 innate lymphoid cells</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2299/5049404?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Lessel D, Gehbauer C, Bramswig N, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;The transcription factor BCL11B is essential for development of the nervous and the immune system, and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Bcl11b&lt;/span&gt; deficiency results in structural brain defects, reduced learning capacity, and impaired immune cell development in mice. However, the precise role of BCL11B in humans is largely unexplored, except for a single patient with a &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;BCL11B&lt;/span&gt; missense mutation, affected by multisystem anomalies and profound immune deficiency. Using massively parallel sequencing we identified 13 patients bearing heterozygous germline alterations in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;BCL11B.&lt;/span&gt; Notably, all of them are affected by global developmental delay with speech impairment and intellectual disability; however, none displayed overt clinical signs of immune deficiency. Six frameshift mutations, two nonsense mutations, one missense mutation, and two chromosomal rearrangements resulting in diminished &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;BCL11B&lt;/span&gt; expression, arose &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;de novo.&lt;/span&gt; A further frameshift mutation was transmitted from a similarly affected mother. Interestingly, the most severely affected patient harbours a missense mutation within a zinc-finger domain of BCL11B, probably affecting the DNA-binding structural interface, similar to the recently published patient. Furthermore, the most C-terminally located premature termination codon mutation fails to rescue the progenitor cell proliferation defect in hippocampal slice cultures from &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Bcl11b&lt;/span&gt;-deficient mice. Concerning the role of BCL11B in the immune system, extensive immune phenotyping of our patients revealed alterations in the T cell compartment and lack of peripheral type 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC2s), consistent with the findings described in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Bcl11b&lt;/span&gt;-deficient mice. Unsupervised analysis of 102 T lymphocyte subpopulations showed that the patients clearly cluster apart from healthy children, further supporting the common aetiology of the disorder. Taken together, we show here that mutations leading either to BCL11B haploinsufficiency or to a truncated BCL11B protein clinically cause a non-syndromic neurodevelopmental delay. In addition, we suggest that missense mutations affecting specific sites within zinc-finger domains might result in distinct and more severe clinical outcomes.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2299
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2311
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy173
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy173</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2486/5050905">
      <title>Reorganization of cortical oscillatory dynamics underlying disinhibition in frontotemporal dementia</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2486/5050905?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Hughes L, Rittman T, Robbins T, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;The distribution of pathology in frontotemporal dementia is anatomically selective, to distinct cortical regions and with differential neurodegeneration across the cortical layers. The cytoarchitecture and connectivity of cortical laminae preferentially supports frequency-specific oscillations and hierarchical information transfer between brain regions. We therefore predicted that in frontotemporal dementia, core functional deficits such as disinhibition would be associated with differences in the frequency spectrum and altered cross-frequency coupling between frontal cortical regions. We examined this hypothesis using a ‘Go-NoGo’ response inhibition paradigm with 18 patients with behavioural variant frontotemporal dementia and 20 healthy aged-matched controls during magnetoencephalography. During Go and NoGo trials, beta desynchronization was severely attenuated in patients. Beta power was associated with increased impulsivity, as measured by the Cambridge Behavioural Inventory, a carer-based questionnaire of changes in everyday behaviour. To quantify the changes in cross-frequency coupling in the frontal lobe, we used dynamic causal modelling to test a family of hierarchical casual models, which included the inferior frontal gyrus, pre-supplementary motor area (preSMA) and primary motor cortex. This analysis revealed evidence for cross-frequency coupling in a fully connected network in both groups. However, in the patient group, we identified a significant loss of reciprocal connectivity of the inferior frontal gyrus, particularly for interactions in the gamma band and for theta to alpha coupling. Importantly, although prefrontal coupling was diminished, gamma connectivity between preSMA and motor cortex was enhanced in patients. We propose that the disruption of behavioural control arises from reduced frequency-specific connectivity of the prefrontal cortex, together with a hyper-synchronous reorganization of connectivity among preSMA and motor regions. These results are supported by preclinical evidence of the selectivity of frontotemporal lobar degeneration on oscillatory dynamics, and provide a clinically relevant yet precise neurophysiological signature of behavioural control as a potential pharmacological target for early phase experimental medicines studies.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2486
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2499
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy176
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy176</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2500/5059461">
      <title>Neurophysiological signatures of Alzheimer’s disease and frontotemporal lobar degeneration: pathology versus phenotype</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2500/5059461?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Sami S, Williams N, Hughes L, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;The disruption of brain networks is characteristic of neurodegenerative dementias. However, it is controversial whether changes in connectivity reflect only the functional anatomy of disease, with selective vulnerability of brain networks, or the specific neurophysiological consequences of different neuropathologies within brain networks. We proposed that the oscillatory dynamics of cortical circuits reflect the tuning of local neural interactions, such that different pathologies are selective in their impact on the frequency spectrum of oscillations, whereas clinical syndromes reflect the anatomical distribution of pathology and physiological change. To test this hypothesis, we used magnetoencephalography from five patient groups, representing dissociated pathological subtypes and distributions across frontal, parietal and temporal lobes: amnestic Alzheimer’s disease, posterior cortical atrophy, and three syndromes associated with frontotemporal lobar degeneration. We measured effective connectivity with graph theory-based measures of local efficiency, using partial directed coherence between sensors. As expected, each disease caused large-scale changes of neurophysiological brain networks, with reductions in local efficiency compared to controls. Critically however, the frequency range of altered connectivity was consistent across clinical syndromes that shared a likely underlying pathology, whilst the localization of changes differed between clinical syndromes. Multivariate pattern analysis of the frequency-specific topographies of local efficiency separated the disorders from each other and from controls (accuracy 62% to 100%, according to the groups’ differences in likely pathology and clinical syndrome). The data indicate that magnetoencephalography has the potential to reveal specific changes in neurophysiology resulting from neurodegenerative disease. Our findings confirm that while clinical syndromes have characteristic anatomical patterns of abnormal connectivity that may be identified with other methods like structural brain imaging, the different mechanisms of neurodegeneration also cause characteristic spectral signatures of physiological coupling that are not accessible with structural imaging nor confounded by the neurovascular signalling of functional MRI. We suggest that these spectral characteristics of altered connectivity are the result of differential disruption of neuronal microstructure and synaptic physiology by Alzheimer’s disease versus frontotemporal lobar degeneration.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2500
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2510
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy180
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy180</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2312/5050181">
      <title>TRPA1/NOX in the soma of trigeminal ganglion neurons mediates migraine-related pain of glyceryl trinitrate in mice</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2312/5050181?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Marone I, De Logu F, Nassini R, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Glyceryl trinitrate is administered as a provocative test for migraine pain. Glyceryl trinitrate causes prolonged mechanical allodynia in rodents, which temporally correlates with delayed glyceryl trinitrate-evoked migraine attacks in patients. However, the underlying mechanism of the allodynia evoked by glyceryl trinitrate is unknown. The proalgesic transient receptor potential ankyrin 1 (TRPA1) channel, expressed by trigeminal nociceptors, is sensitive to oxidative stress and is targeted by nitric oxide or its by-products. Herein, we explored the role of TRPA1 in glyceryl trinitrate-evoked allodynia. Systemic administration of glyceryl trinitrate elicited in the mouse periorbital area an early and transient vasodilatation and a delayed and prolonged mechanical allodynia. The systemic, intrathecal or local administration of selective enzyme inhibitors revealed that nitric oxide, liberated from the parent drug by aldehyde dehydrogenase 2 (ALDH2), initiates but does not maintain allodynia. The central and the final phases of allodynia were respectively associated with generation of reactive oxygen and carbonyl species within the trigeminal ganglion. Allodynia was absent in TRPA1-deficient mice and was reversed by TRPA1 antagonists. Knockdown of neuronal TRPA1 by intrathecally administered antisense oligonucleotide and selective deletion of TRPA1 from sensory neurons in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Advillin-Cre&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Trpa1fl/fl&lt;/span&gt; mice revealed that nitric oxide-dependent oxidative and carbonylic stress generation is due to TRPA1 stimulation, and resultant NADPH oxidase 1 (NOX1) and NOX2 activation in the soma of trigeminal ganglion neurons. Early periorbital vasodilatation evoked by glyceryl trinitrate was attenuated by ALDH2 inhibition but was unaffected by TRPA1 blockade. Antagonists of the calcitonin gene-related peptide receptor did not affect the vasodilatation but partially inhibited allodynia. Thus, although both periorbital allodynia and vasodilatation evoked by glyceryl trinitrate are initiated by nitric oxide, they are temporally and mechanistically distinct. While vasodilatation is due to a direct nitric oxide action in the vascular smooth muscle, allodynia is a neuronal phenomenon mediated by TRPA1 activation and ensuing oxidative stress. The autocrine pathway, sustained by TRPA1 and NOX1/2 within neuronal cell bodies of trigeminal ganglia, may sensitize meningeal nociceptors and second order trigeminal neurons to elicit periorbital allodynia, and could be of relevance for migraine-like headaches evoked by glyceryl trinitrate in humans.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2312
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2328
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy177
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy177</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2445/5047998">
      <title>Localizing parkinsonism based on focal brain lesions</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2445/5047998?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Joutsa J, Horn A, Hsu J, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Bradykinesia, rigidity, and tremor frequently co-occur, a clinical syndrome known as parkinsonism. Because this syndrome is commonly seen in Parkinson’s disease, symptoms are often attributed to cell loss in the substantia nigra. However, parkinsonism occurs in several other neurological disorders and often fails to correlate with nigrostriatal pathology, raising the question of which brain region(s) cause this syndrome. Here, we studied cases of new-onset parkinsonism following focal brain lesions. We identified 29 cases, only 31% of which hit the substantia nigra. Lesions were located in a variety of different cortical and subcortical locations. To determine whether these heterogeneous lesion locations were part of a common brain network, we leveraged the human brain connectome and a recently validated technique termed lesion network mapping. Lesion locations causing parkinsonism were functionally connected to a common network of regions including the midbrain, basal ganglia, cingulate cortex, and cerebellum. The most sensitive and specific connectivity was to the claustrum. This lesion connectivity pattern matched atrophy patterns seen in Parkinson’s disease, progressive supranuclear palsy, and multiple system atrophy, suggesting a shared neuroanatomical substrate for parkinsonism. Lesion connectivity also predicted medication response and matched the pattern of effective deep brain stimulation, suggesting relevance as a treatment target. Our results, based on causal brain lesions, lend insight into the localization of parkinsonism, one of the most common syndromes in neurology. Because many patients with parkinsonism fail to respond to dopaminergic medication, these results may aid the development of alternative treatments.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2445
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2456
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy161
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy161</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2343/5046343">
      <title>CHP1 reduction ameliorates spinal muscular atrophy pathology by restoring calcineurin activity and endocytosis</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2343/5046343?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Janzen E, Mendoza-Ferreira N, Hosseinibarkooie S, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Autosomal recessive spinal muscular atrophy (SMA), the leading genetic cause of infant lethality, is caused by homozygous loss of the survival motor neuron 1 (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SMN1&lt;/span&gt;) gene. SMA disease severity inversely correlates with the number of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SMN2&lt;/span&gt; copies, which in contrast to &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SMN1&lt;/span&gt;, mainly produce aberrantly spliced transcripts. Recently, the first SMA therapy based on antisense oligonucleotides correcting &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SMN2&lt;/span&gt; splicing, namely SPINRAZA&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt;, has been approved. Nevertheless, in type I SMA-affected individuals—representing 60% of SMA patients—the elevated SMN level may still be insufficient to restore motor neuron function lifelong. Plastin 3 (PLS3) and neurocalcin delta (NCALD) are two SMN-independent protective modifiers identified in humans and proved to be effective across various SMA animal models. Both PLS3 overexpression and NCALD downregulation protect against SMA by restoring impaired endocytosis; however, the exact mechanism of this protection is largely unknown. Here, we identified calcineurin-like EF-hand protein 1 (CHP1) as a novel PLS3 interacting protein using a yeast-two-hybrid screen. Co-immunoprecipitation and pull-down assays confirmed a direct interaction between CHP1 and PLS3. Although CHP1 is ubiquitously present, it is particularly abundant in the central nervous system and at SMA-relevant sites including motor neuron growth cones and neuromuscular junctions. Strikingly, we found elevated CHP1 levels in SMA mice. Congruently, CHP1 downregulation restored impaired axonal growth in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Smn&lt;/span&gt;-depleted NSC34 motor neuron-like cells, SMA zebrafish and primary murine SMA motor neurons. Most importantly, subcutaneous injection of low-dose SMN antisense oligonucleotide in pre-symptomatic mice doubled the survival rate of severely-affected SMA mice, while additional CHP1 reduction by genetic modification prolonged survival further by 1.6-fold. Moreover, CHP1 reduction further ameliorated SMA disease hallmarks including electrophysiological defects, smaller neuromuscular junction size, impaired maturity of neuromuscular junctions and smaller muscle fibre size compared to low-dose SMN antisense oligonucleotide alone. In NSC34 cells, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Chp1&lt;/span&gt; knockdown tripled macropinocytosis whereas clathrin-mediated endocytosis remained unaffected. Importantly, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Chp1&lt;/span&gt; knockdown restored macropinocytosis in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Smn&lt;/span&gt;-depleted cells by elevating calcineurin phosphatase activity. CHP1 is an inhibitor of calcineurin, which collectively dephosphorylates proteins involved in endocytosis, and is therefore crucial in synaptic vesicle endocytosis. Indeed, we found marked hyperphosphorylation of dynamin 1 in SMA motor neurons, which was restored to control level by the heterozygous &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Chp1&lt;/span&gt; mutant allele. Taken together, we show that CHP1 is a novel SMA modifier that directly interacts with PLS3, and that CHP1 reduction ameliorates SMA pathology by counteracting impaired endocytosis. Most importantly, we demonstrate that CHP1 reduction is a promising SMN-independent therapeutic target for a combinatorial SMA therapy.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2343
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2361
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy167
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy167</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2392/5046342">
      <title>De novo variants in GABRA2 and GABRA5 alter receptor function and contribute to early-onset epilepsy</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2392/5046342?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Butler K, Moody O, Schuler E, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;GABA&lt;sub&gt;A&lt;/sub&gt; receptors are ligand-gated anion channels that are important regulators of neuronal inhibition. Mutations in several genes encoding receptor subunits have been identified in patients with various types of epilepsy, ranging from mild febrile seizures to severe epileptic encephalopathy. Using whole-genome sequencing, we identified a novel &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;de novo&lt;/span&gt; missense variant in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRA5&lt;/span&gt; (c.880G &amp;gt; C, p.V294L) in a patient with severe early-onset epilepsy and developmental delay. Targeted resequencing of 279 additional epilepsy patients identified 19 rare variants from nine GABA&lt;sub&gt;A&lt;/sub&gt; receptor genes, including a novel &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;de novo&lt;/span&gt; missense variant in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRA2&lt;/span&gt; (c.875C &amp;gt; A, p.T292K) and a recurrent missense variant in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRB3&lt;/span&gt; (c.902C &amp;gt; T, p.P301L). Patients with the &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRA2&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRB3&lt;/span&gt; variants also presented with severe epilepsy and developmental delay. We evaluated the effects of the &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRA5&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRA2&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRB3&lt;/span&gt; missense variants on receptor function using whole-cell patch-clamp recordings from human embryonic kidney 293T cells expressing appropriate α, β and γ subunits. The &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRA5&lt;/span&gt; p.V294L variant produced receptors that were 10-times more sensitive to GABA but had reduced maximal GABA-evoked current due to increased receptor desensitization. The &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRA2&lt;/span&gt; p.T292K variant reduced channel expression and produced mutant channels that were tonically open, even in the absence of GABA. Receptors containing the &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRB3&lt;/span&gt; p.P301L variant were less sensitive to GABA and produced less GABA-evoked current. These results provide the first functional evidence that &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;de novo&lt;/span&gt; variants in the &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRA5&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;GABRA2&lt;/span&gt; genes contribute to early-onset epilepsy and developmental delay, and demonstrate that epilepsy can result from reduced neuronal inhibition via a wide range of alterations in GABA&lt;sub&gt;A&lt;/sub&gt; receptor function.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2392
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2405
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy171
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy171</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e62/5045537">
      <title>Will FTLD-tau work for all when FTDP-17 retires?</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e62/5045537?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ygland E, Landqvist Waldö M, Englund E, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;Sir,&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e62
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e62
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy178
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy178</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e63/5045538">
      <title>Reply: Will FTLD-tau work for all when FTDP-17 retires?</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e63/5045538?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Forrest S, Kril J, Halliday G. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;Sir,&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e63
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e63
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy179
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy179</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2457/5043552">
      <title>Trisomy of human chromosome 21 enhances amyloid-β deposition independently of an extra copy of APP</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2457/5043552?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Wiseman F, Pulford L, Barkus C, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Down syndrome, caused by trisomy of chromosome 21, is the single most common risk factor for early-onset Alzheimer’s disease. Worldwide approximately 6 million people have Down syndrome, and all these individuals will develop the hallmark amyloid plaques and neurofibrillary tangles of Alzheimer’s disease by the age of 40 and the vast majority will go on to develop dementia. Triplication of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;, a gene on chromosome 21, is sufficient to cause early-onset Alzheimer’s disease in the absence of Down syndrome. However, whether triplication of other chromosome 21 genes influences disease pathogenesis in the context of Down syndrome is unclear. Here we show, in a mouse model, that triplication of chromosome 21 genes other than &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt; increases amyloid-β aggregation, deposition of amyloid-β plaques and worsens associated cognitive deficits. This indicates that triplication of chromosome 21 genes other than &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt; is likely to have an important role to play in Alzheimer’s disease pathogenesis in individuals who have Down syndrome. We go on to show that the effect of trisomy of chromosome 21 on amyloid-β aggregation correlates with an unexpected shift in soluble amyloid-β 40/42 ratio. This alteration in amyloid-β isoform ratio occurs independently of a change in the carboxypeptidase activity of the γ-secretase complex, which cleaves the peptide from APP, or the rate of extracellular clearance of amyloid-β. These new mechanistic insights into the role of triplication of genes on chromosome 21, other than &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;, in the development of Alzheimer’s disease in individuals who have Down syndrome may have implications for the treatment of this common cause of neurodegeneration.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2457
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2474
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy159
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy159</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2280/5043196">
      <title>Intronic pentanucleotide TTTCA repeat insertion in the SAMD12 gene causes familial cortical myoclonic tremor with epilepsy type 1</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2280/5043196?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Cen Z, Jiang Z, Chen Y, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Familial cortical myoclonic tremor with epilepsy is an autosomal dominant neurodegenerative disease, characterized by cortical tremor and epileptic seizures. Although four subtypes (types 1–4) mapped on different chromosomes (8q24, 2p11.1-q12.2, 5p15.31-p15.1 and 3q26.32-3q28) have been reported, the causative gene has not yet been identified. Here, we report the genetic study in a cohort of 20 Chinese pedigrees with familial cortical myoclonic tremor with epilepsy. Linkage and haplotype analysis in 11 pedigrees revealed maximum two-point logarithm of the odds (LOD) scores from 1.64 to 3.77 (LOD scores in five pedigrees were &amp;gt;3.0) in chromosomal region 8q24 and narrowed the candidate region to an interval of 4.9 Mb. Using whole-genome sequencing, long-range polymerase chain reaction and repeat-primed polymerase chain reaction, we identified an intronic pentanucleotide (TTTCA)&lt;sub&gt;n&lt;/sub&gt; insertion in the &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SAMD12&lt;/span&gt; gene as the cause, which co-segregated with the disease among the 11 pedigrees mapped on 8q24 and additional seven unmapped pedigrees. Only two pedigrees did not contain the (TTTCA)&lt;sub&gt;n&lt;/sub&gt; insertion. Repeat-primed polymerase chain reaction revealed that the sizes of (TTTCA)&lt;sub&gt;n&lt;/sub&gt; insertion in all affected members were larger than 105 repeats. The same pentanucleotide insertion (ATTTCATTTC)&lt;sub&gt;58&lt;/sub&gt; has been reported to form RNA foci resulting in neurotoxicity in spinocerebellar ataxia type 37, which suggests the similar pathogenic process in familial cortical myoclonic tremor with epilepsy type 1.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2280
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2288
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy160
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy160</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2406/5043436">
      <title>Left temporal lobe language network connectivity in temporal lobe epilepsy</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2406/5043436?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Trimmel K, van Graan A, Caciagli L, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Impairment of naming function is a critical problem for temporal lobe epilepsy patients, yet the neural correlates of the disruption of temporal lobe language networks are poorly understood. Using functional MRI, we investigated the activation and task-related functional connectivity of left temporal lobe language networks and their relation to clinical naming performance and disease characteristics. We studied 59 adult patients with temporal lobe epilepsy (35 left temporal lobe epilepsy) and 32 healthy controls with auditory and visual naming functional MRI tasks. Time series of activation maxima in the left posterior inferior temporal lobe were extracted to create a psychophysiological interaction regressor for subsequent seed-based whole-brain task-related functional connectivity analyses. Correlational analyses were performed to assess the association of functional MRI activation and functional connectivity with clinical naming scores, age of onset of epilepsy, and duration of epilepsy. Auditory naming elicited activation in the left posterior inferior temporal gyrus and visual naming in the left fusiform gyrus across all groups. Activations in the left inferior temporal gyrus, left thalamus and left supplementary motor region during auditory naming as well as left fusiform activations during picture naming correlated with better clinical naming performance. Functional connectivity analyses indicated coupling of left posterior inferior temporal regions to bilateral anterior and posterior temporal lobe regions and the bilateral inferior precentral gyrus as well as contralateral occipital cortex. Stronger functional connectivity was associated with better clinical naming performance in all groups. In patients with left temporal lobe epilepsy only, functional connectivity increased with later age of onset of epilepsy and shorter disease duration. This suggests that onset of seizures early in life and prolonged disease duration lead to disrupted recruitment of temporal lobe networks ipsilateral to the seizure focus, which might account for naming deficits in temporal lobe epilepsy.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2406
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2418
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy164
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy164</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2272/5042840">
      <title>Interplay between spinal cord and cerebral cortex metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2272/5042840?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Marini C, Morbelli S, Cistaro A, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;We recently reported the potential of Hough transform in delineating spinal cord metabolism by &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-fluorodeoxyglucose PET/CT scanning in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The present study aimed to verify the relationship between spinal cord and brain metabolism in 44 prospectively recruited patients affected by amyotrophic lateral sclerosis submitted to &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-fluorodeoxyglucose brain and whole-body PET/CT. Patients were studied to highlight the presence of brain hypo- or hypermetabolism with respect to healthy controls, and multiple regression analysis was performed to evaluate the correlation between spinal cord and brain metabolism. Our results confirmed higher &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-fluorodeoxyglucose uptake in both cervical and dorsal spinal cord in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with respect to controls. This finding was paralleled by the opposite pattern in the brain cortex that showed a generalized reduction in tracer uptake. This hypometabolism was particularly evident in wide regions of the frontal-dorsolateral cortex while it did not involve the midbrain. Bulbar and spinal disease onset was associated with similar degree of metabolic activation in the spinal cord. However, among spinal onset patients, upper limb presentation was associated with a more pronounced metabolic activation of cervical segment. Obtained data suggest a differential neuro-pathological state or temporal sequence in disease progression.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2272
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2279
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy152
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy152</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e64/5038576">
      <title>Corrigendum</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e64/5038576?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author />
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;Jie Zhang, Wei Cheng, Zhaowen Liu, Kai Zhang, Xu Lei, Ye Yao, Benjamin Becker, Yicen Liu, Keith M. Kendrick, Guangming Lu and Jianfeng Feng. Neural, electrophysiological and anatomical basis of brain-network variability and its characteristic changes in mental disorders. Brain 2016; 139: 2307–21; doi:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="article.aspx?volume=&amp;amp;page="&gt;10.1093/brain/aww143&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e64
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e64
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy169
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy169</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e65/5039694">
      <title>Corrigendum</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e65/5039694?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author />
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;Cary S. Kogan, Isabelle Boutet, Kim Cornish, Shahin Zangenehpour, Kathy T. Mullen, Jeanette J. A. Holden, Vazken M. Der Kaloustian, Eva Andermann and Avi Chaudhuri. Differential impact of the &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;FMR1&lt;/span&gt; gene on visual processing in fragile X syndrome. Brain 2004; 127: 591–601; doi:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="article.aspx?volume=&amp;amp;page="&gt;10.1093/brain/awh069&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e65
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e65
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy170
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy170</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2419/5039696">
      <title>Somatic copy number gains of α-synuclein (SNCA) in Parkinson’s disease and multiple system atrophy brains</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2419/5039696?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Mokretar K, Pease D, Taanman J, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;The α-synuclein protein, encoded by &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt;, has a key role in the pathogenesis of Parkinson’s disease and other synucleinopathies. Although usually sporadic, Parkinson’s disease can result from inherited copy number variants in &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt; and other genes. We have hypothesized a role of somatic &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt; mutations, leading to mosaicism, in sporadic synucleinopathies. The evidence for mosaicism in healthy and diseased brain is increasing rapidly, with somatic copy number gains of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt; reported in Alzheimer’s brain. Here we demonstrate somatic &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt; copy number gains in synucleinopathies (Parkinson’s disease and multiple system atrophy), focusing on substantia nigra. We selected sporadic cases with relatively young onset or short disease duration, and first excluded high level copy number variant mosaicism by DNA analysis using digital PCR for &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt;, and/or customized array comparative genomic hybridization. To detect low level &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt; copy number variant mosaicism, we used fluorescent &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;in situ&lt;/span&gt; hybridization with oligonucleotide custom-designed probes for &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt;, validated on brain and fibroblasts with known copy number variants. We determined &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt; copy number in nigral dopaminergic neurons and other cells in frozen nigra sections from 40 cases with Parkinson’s disease and five with multiple system atrophy, and 25 controls, in a blinded fashion. Parkinson’s disease cases were significantly more likely than controls to have any &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt; gains in dopaminergic neurons (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P = &lt;/span&gt;0.0036), and overall (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P = &lt;/span&gt;0.0052). The average proportion of dopaminergic neurons with gains in each nigra was significantly higher in Parkinson’s disease than controls (0.78% versus 0.45%; &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P = &lt;/span&gt;0.017). There was a negative correlation between the proportion of dopaminergic neurons with gains and onset age in Parkinson’s disease (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P = &lt;/span&gt;0.013), but not with disease duration, or age of death in cases or controls. Cases with tremor at onset were less likely to have gains (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P = &lt;/span&gt;0.035). All multiple system atrophy cases had gains, and the highest levels in dopaminergic neurons were in two of these cases (2.76%, 2.48%). We performed selective validation with different probes after dye swapping. All three control probes used showed minimal or no gains (≤0.1% in dopaminergic neurons). We also found occasional &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt; gains in frontal neurons of cases with Parkinson’s disease, and the putamen of one multiple system atrophy case. We present evidence of somatic &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt; gains in brain, more commonly in nigral dopaminergic neurons of Parkinson’s disease than controls, negatively correlated with onset age, and possibly commonest in some multiple system atrophy cases. Somatic &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;SNCA&lt;/span&gt; gains may be a risk factor for sporadic synucleinopathies, or a result of the disease process.10.1093/brain/awy157_video1awy157media15813519976001&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2419
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2431
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy157
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy157</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2362/5036378">
      <title>Immune-evasive gene switch enables regulated delivery of chondroitinase after spinal cord injury</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2362/5036378?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Burnside E, De Winter F, Didangelos A, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Chondroitinase ABC is a promising preclinical therapy that promotes functional neuroplasticity after CNS injury by degrading extracellular matrix inhibitors. Efficient delivery of chondroitinase ABC to the injured mammalian spinal cord can be achieved by viral vector transgene delivery. This approach dramatically modulates injury pathology and restores sensorimotor functions. However, clinical development of this therapy is limited by a lack of ability to exert control over chondroitinase gene expression. Prior experimental gene regulation platforms are likely to be incompatible with the non-resolving adaptive immune response known to occur following spinal cord injury. Therefore, here we apply a novel immune-evasive dual vector system, in which the chondroitinase gene is under a doxycycline inducible regulatory switch, utilizing a chimeric transactivator designed to evade T cell recognition. Using this novel vector system, we demonstrate tight temporal control of chondroitinase ABC gene expression, effectively removing treatment upon removal of doxycycline. This enables a comparison of short and long-term gene therapy paradigms in the treatment of clinically-relevant cervical level contusion injuries in adult rats. We reveal that transient treatment (2.5 weeks) is sufficient to promote improvement in sensory axon conduction and ladder walking performance. However, in tasks requiring skilled reaching and grasping, only long term treatment (8 weeks) leads to significantly improved function, with rats able to accurately grasp and retrieve sugar pellets. The late emergence of skilled hand function indicates enhanced neuroplasticity and connectivity and correlates with increased density of vGlut1+ innervation in spinal cord grey matter, particularly in lamina III–IV above and below the injury. Thus, our novel gene therapy system provides an experimental tool to study temporal effects of extracellular matrix digestion as well as an encouraging step towards generating a safer chondroitinase gene therapy strategy, longer term administration of which increases neuroplasticity and recovery of descending motor control. This preclinical study could have a significant impact for tetraplegic individuals, for whom recovery of hand function is an important determinant of independence, and supports the ongoing development of chondroitinase gene therapy towards clinical application for the treatment of spinal cord injury.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2362
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2381
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy158
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy158</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2432/5036773">
      <title>Neurophysiological correlates of bradykinesia in Parkinson’s disease</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2432/5036773?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bologna M, Guerra A, Paparella G, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Many neurophysiological abnormalities have been described in the primary motor cortex of patients with Parkinson’s disease. However, it is unclear whether there is any relationship between them and bradykinesia, one of the cardinal motor features of the condition. In the present study we aimed to investigate whether objective measures of bradykinesia in Parkinson’s disease have any relationship with neurophysiological measures in primary motor cortex as assessed by means of transcranial magnetic stimulation techniques. Twenty-two patients with Parkinson’s disease and 18 healthy subjects were enrolled. Objective measurements of repetitive finger tapping (amplitude, speed and decrement) were obtained using a motion analysis system. The excitability of primary motor cortex was assessed by recording the input/output curve of the motor-evoked potentials and using a conditioning-test paradigm for the assessment of short-interval intracortical inhibition and facilitation. Plasticity-like mechanisms in primary motor cortex were indexed according to the amplitude changes in motor-evoked potentials after the paired associative stimulation protocol. Patients were assessed in two sessions, i.e. OFF and ON medication. A canonical correlation analysis was used to test for relationships between the kinematic and neurophysiological variables. Patients with Parkinson’s disease tapped more slowly and with smaller amplitude than normal, and displayed decrement as tapping progressed. They also had steeper input/output curves, reduced short-interval intracortical inhibition and a reduced response to the paired associative stimulation protocol. Within the patient group, bradykinesia features correlated with the slope of the input/output curve and the after-effects of the paired associative stimulation protocol. Although dopaminergic therapy improved movement kinematics as well as neurophysiological measures, there was no relationship between them. In conclusion, neurophysiological changes in primary motor cortex relate to bradykinesia in patients with Parkinson’s disease, although other mechanisms sensitive to dopamine levels must also play a role.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2432
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2444
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy155
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy155</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2475/5036359">
      <title>Effects of amyloid pathology and neurodegeneration on cognitive change in cognitively normal adults</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2475/5036359?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bilgel M, An Y, Helphrey J, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Understanding short-term cognitive decline in relation to Alzheimer’s neuroimaging biomarkers in early stages of the development of neuropathology and neurodegeneration will inform participant recruitment and monitoring strategies in clinical trials aimed at prevention of cognitive impairment and dementia. We assessed associations among neuroimaging measures of cerebral amyloid pathology, a hallmark Alzheimer’s neuropathology, hippocampal atrophy, and prospective cognition among 171 cognitively normal Baltimore Longitudinal Study of Aging participants (baseline age 56–95 years, 48% female, 562 cognitive assessments, 3.7 years follow-up). We categorized each individual based on dichotomous amyloid pathology (A) and hippocampal neurodegeneration (N) status at baseline: A−N−, A+N−, A−N+, A+N+. We conducted linear mixed effects analyses to assess cross-sectional and longitudinal trends in cognitive test &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;z&lt;/span&gt;-scores by amyloid and neurodegeneration group. To investigate the effects of amyloid dose and degree of hippocampal atrophy, we assessed the associations of continuous mean cortical amyloid level and hippocampal volume with cognitive performance among individuals with detectable amyloid pathology at baseline. Individuals with amyloidosis or hippocampal atrophy had steeper longitudinal declines in verbal episodic memory and learning compared to those with neither condition (A+N− versus A−N−: β = − 0.069, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.017; A−N+ versus A−N−: β = − 0.081, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.025). Among individuals with hippocampal atrophy, amyloid positivity was associated with steeper declines in verbal memory (β = − 0.123, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.015), visual memory (β = − 0.121, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.036), language (β = − 0.144, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.0004), and mental status (β = − 0.242, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.002). Similarly, among individuals with amyloidosis, hippocampal atrophy was associated with steeper declines in verbal memory (β = − 0.135, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.004), visual memory (β = − 0.141, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.010), language (β = − 0.108, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.006), and mental status (β = − 0.165, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.022). Presence of both amyloidosis and hippocampal atrophy was associated with greater declines than would be expected by their additive contributions in visual memory (β = − 0.139, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.036), language (β = − 0.132, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.005), and mental status (β = − 0.170, &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 0.049). Neither amyloidosis nor hippocampal atrophy was predictive of declines in executive function, processing speed, or visuospatial ability. Among individuals with amyloidosis, higher baseline amyloid level was associated with lower concurrent visual memory, steeper declines in language, visuospatial ability, and mental status, whereas greater hippocampal atrophy was associated with steeper declines in category fluency. Our results suggest that both amyloid pathology and neurodegeneration have disadvantageous, in part synergistic, effects on prospective cognition. These cognitive effects are detectable early among cognitively normal individuals with amyloidosis, who are in preclinical stages of Alzheimer’s disease according to research criteria. Our findings highlight the importance of early intervention to target both amyloidosis and atrophy to preserve cognitive function before further damage occurs.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2475
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2485
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy150
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy150</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e60/5035368">
      <title>Late onset epilepsy and Alzheimer’s disease: exploring the dual pathogenic role of amyloid-β</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e60/5035368?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Costa C, Romoli M, Calabresi P. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;Sir,&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e60
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e60
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy162
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy162</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e61/5035367">
      <title>Reply: Late onset epilepsy and Alzheimer’s disease: exploring the dual pathogenic role of amyloid-β</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e61/5035367?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Sen A, Husain M. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;Sir,&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e61
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e61
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy163
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy163</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2255/5025743">
      <title>Is Parkinson’s disease a lysosomal disorder?</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2255/5025743?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Klein A, Mazzulli J. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Common forms of Parkinson’s disease have long been described as idiopathic, with no single penetrant genetic factor capable of influencing disease aetiology. Recent genetic studies indicate a clear association of variants within several lysosomal genes as risk factors for idiopathic Parkinson’s disease. The emergence of novel variants suggest that the aetiology of idiopathic Parkinson’s disease may be explained by the interaction of several partially penetrant mutations that, while seemingly complex, all appear to converge on cellular clearance pathways. These newly evolving data are consistent with mechanistic studies linking α-synuclein toxicity to lysosomal abnormalities, and indicate that idiopathic Parkinson’s disease resembles features of Mendelian lysosomal storage disorders at a genetic and biochemical level. These findings offer novel pathways to exploit for the development of disease-altering therapies for idiopathic Parkinson’s disease that target specific components of the lysosomal system.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2255
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2262
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy147
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy147</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2329/5025745">
      <title>Impaired plasticity of macrophages in X-linked adrenoleukodystrophy</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2329/5025745?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Weinhofer I, Zierfuss B, Hametner S, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;X-linked adrenoleukodystrophy is caused by ATP-binding cassette transporter D1 (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;ABCD1&lt;/span&gt;) mutations and manifests by default as slowly progressive spinal cord axonopathy with associated demyelination (adrenomyloneuropathy). In 60% of male cases, however, X-linked adrenoleukodystrophy converts to devastating cerebral inflammation and demyelination (cerebral adrenoleukodystrophy) with infiltrating blood-derived monocytes and macrophages and cytotoxic T cells that can only be stopped by allogeneic haematopoietic stem cell transplantation or gene therapy at an early stage of the disease. Recently, we identified monocytes/macrophages but not T cells to be severely affected metabolically by ABCD1 deficiency. Here we found by whole transcriptome analysis that, although monocytes of patients with X-linked adrenoleukodystrophy have normal capacity for macrophage differentiation and phagocytosis, they are pro-inflammatory skewed also in patients with adrenomyloneuropathy in the absence of cerebral inflammation. Following lipopolysaccharide activation, the ingestion of myelin debris, normally triggering anti-inflammatory polarization, did not fully reverse the pro-inflammatory status of X-linked adrenoleukodystrophy macrophages. Immunohistochemistry on post-mortem cerebral adrenoleukodystrophy lesions reflected the activation pattern by prominent presence of enlarged lipid-laden macrophages strongly positive for the pro-inflammatory marker co-stimulatory molecule CD86. Comparative analyses of lesions with matching macrophage density in cases of cerebral adrenoleukodystrophy and acute multiple sclerosis showed a similar extent of pro-inflammatory activation but a striking reduction of anti-inflammatory mannose receptor (CD206) and haemoglobin-haptoglobin receptor (CD163) expression on cerebral adrenoleukodystrophy macrophages. Accordingly, ABCD1-deficiency leads to an impaired plasticity of macrophages that is reflected in incomplete establishment of anti-inflammatory responses, thus possibly contributing to the devastating rapidly progressive demyelination in cerebral adrenoleukodystrophy that only in rare cases arrests spontaneously. These findings emphasize monocytes/macrophages as crucial therapeutic targets for preventing or stopping myelin destruction in patients with X-linked adrenoleukodystrophy.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2329
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2342
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy127
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy127</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2382/5025690">
      <title>Serum neurofilament as a predictor of disease worsening and brain and spinal cord atrophy in multiple sclerosis</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2382/5025690?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Barro C, Benkert P, Disanto G, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Neuro-axonal injury is a key factor in the development of permanent disability in multiple sclerosis. Neurofilament light chain in peripheral blood has recently emerged as a biofluid marker reflecting neuro-axonal damage in this disease. We aimed at comparing serum neurofilament light chain levels in multiple sclerosis and healthy controls, to determine their association with measures of disease activity and their ability to predict future clinical worsening as well as brain and spinal cord volume loss. Neurofilament light chain was measured by single molecule array assay in 2183 serum samples collected as part of an ongoing cohort study from 259 patients with multiple sclerosis (189 relapsing and 70 progressive) and 259 healthy control subjects. Clinical assessment, serum sampling and MRI were done annually; median follow-up time was 6.5 years. Brain volumes were quantified by structural image evaluation using normalization of atrophy, and structural image evaluation using normalization of atrophy, cross-sectional, cervical spinal cord volumes using spinal cord image analyser (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;cordial&lt;/span&gt;). Results were analysed using ordinary linear regression models and generalized estimating equation modelling. Serum neurofilament light chain was higher in patients with a clinically isolated syndrome or relapsing remitting multiple sclerosis as well as in patients with secondary or primary progressive multiple sclerosis than in healthy controls (age adjusted &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P &amp;lt; &lt;/span&gt;0.001 for both). Serum neurofilament light chain above the 90th percentile of healthy controls values was an independent predictor of Expanded Disability Status Scale worsening in the subsequent year (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P &amp;lt; &lt;/span&gt;0.001). The probability of Expanded Disability Status Scale worsening gradually increased by higher serum neurofilament light chain percentile category. Contrast enhancing and new/enlarging lesions were independently associated with increased serum neurofilament light chain (17.8% and 4.9% increase per lesion respectively; &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P &amp;lt; &lt;/span&gt;0.001). The higher the serum neurofilament light chain percentile level, the more pronounced was future brain and cervical spinal volume loss: serum neurofilament light chain above the 97.5th percentile was associated with an additional average loss in brain volume of 1.5% (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P &amp;lt; &lt;/span&gt;0.001) and spinal cord volume of 2.5% over 5 years (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P = &lt;/span&gt;0.009). Serum neurofilament light chain correlated with concurrent and future clinical and MRI measures of disease activity and severity. High serum neurofilament light chain levels were associated with both brain and spinal cord volume loss. Neurofilament light chain levels are a real-time, easy to measure marker of neuro-axonal injury that is conceptually more comprehensive than brain MRI.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2382
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2391
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy154
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy154</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e58/5009394">
      <title>Social communication in Tourette syndrome: a glimpse at the contribution of the insula and the prefrontal cortex</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e58/5009394?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Vicario C, Martino D. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;Sir,&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e58
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e58
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy140
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy140</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e59/5009393">
      <title>Reply: Social communication in Tourette syndrome: a glimpse at the contribution of the insula and the prefrontal cortex</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/e59/5009393?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Albin R. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;Sir,&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e59
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">e59
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy144
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy144</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2263/4999724">
      <title>Distinct HLA associations of LGI1 and CASPR2-antibody diseases</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2263/4999724?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Binks S, Varley J, Lee W, et al. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;The recent biochemical distinction between antibodies against leucine-rich, glioma-inactivated-1 (LGI1), contactin-associated protein-2 (CASPR2) and intracellular epitopes of voltage-gated potassium-channels (VGKCs) demands aetiological explanations. Given established associations between human leucocyte antigen (HLA) alleles and adverse drug reactions, and our clinical observation of frequent adverse drugs reactions in patients with LGI1 antibodies, we compared HLA alleles between healthy controls (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; = 5553) and 111 Caucasian patients with VGKC-complex autoantibodies. In patients with LGI1 antibodies (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; = 68), HLA-DRB1*07:01 was strongly represented [odds ratio = 27.6 (95% confidence interval 12.9–72.2), &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 4.1 × 10&lt;sup&gt;−26&lt;/sup&gt;]. In contrast, patients with CASPR2 antibodies (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; = 31) showed over-representation of HLA-DRB1*11:01 [odds ratio = 9.4 (95% confidence interval 4.6–19.3), &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt; = 5.7 × 10&lt;sup&gt;−6&lt;/sup&gt;]. Other allelic associations for patients with LGI1 antibodies reflected linkage, and significant haplotypic associations included HLA-DRB1*07:01-DQA1*02:01-DQB1*02:02, by comparison to DRB1*11:01-DQA1*05:01-DQB1*03:01 in CASPR2-antibody patients. Conditional analysis in LGI1-antibody patients resolved further independent class I and II associations. By comparison, patients with both LGI1 and CASPR2 antibodies (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; = 3) carried yet another complement of HLA variants, and patients with intracellular VGKC antibodies (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; = 9) lacked significant HLA associations. Within LGI1- or CASPR2-antibody patients, HLA associations did not correlate with clinical features. &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;In silico&lt;/span&gt; predictions identified unique CASPR2- and LGI1-derived peptides potentially presented by the respective over-represented HLA molecules. These highly significant HLA associations dichotomize the underlying immunology in patients with LGI1 or CASPR2 antibodies, and inform T cell specificities and cellular interactions at disease initiation.10.1093/brain/awy109_video1awy109media15796480660001&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2263
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2271
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy109
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy109</guid>
    </item>
    <item 
      xmlns:rdf="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2245/4995212">
      <title>A new framework for conceptualizing symptoms in frontotemporal dementia: from animal models to the clinic</title>
      <link>https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/141/8/2245/4995212?rss=1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Wong S, Balleine B, Kumfor F. </author>
      <description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;&lt;div class="boxTitle"&gt;Abstract&lt;/div&gt;Behavioural-variant frontotemporal dementia is characterized by a number of ostensibly disparate clinical features, which have largely been considered independently. This update proposes an integrated conceptual framework for these symptoms, by bringing together findings from animal studies, functional neuroimaging and behavioural neurology. The combined evidence indicates that many of the clinical symptoms––such as altered eating behaviour; overspending and susceptibility to scams; reduced empathy and socially inappropriate behaviour; apathy and stereotyped/ritualistic behaviour––can be conceptualized as a common underlying deficiency in goal-directed behaviour and the concomitant emergence of habits. This view is supported by similarities between the characteristic patterns of frontostriatal and insular atrophy in behavioural-variant frontotemporal dementia and the circuitry of homologous brain regions responsible for goal-directed and habitual behaviour in animals. Appreciating the impact of disturbance in goal-directed behaviour provides a new, integrated understanding of the common mechanisms underpinning prototypical clinical symptoms in behavioural-variant frontotemporal dementia. Furthermore, by drawing parallels between animal and clinical research, this translational approach has important implications for the development and evaluation of novel therapeutic treatments, from animal models through to behavioural interventions and clinical trials in humans.10.1093/brain/awy123_video1awy123media15796485557001&lt;/span&gt;</description>
      <prism:volume 
        xmlns:prism="prism">141
      </prism:volume>
      <prism:number 
        xmlns:prism="prism">8
      </prism:number>
      <prism:startingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2245
      </prism:startingPage>
      <prism:endingPage 
        xmlns:prism="prism">2254
      </prism:endingPage>
      <prism:doi 
        xmlns:prism="prism">10.1093/brain/awy123
      </prism:doi>
      <guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy123</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>